CRAIG NEESON

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

craigneeson@hotmail.co.uk 07517099522

https://craigneeson.co.uk/ https://github.com/cneeson https://uk.linkedin.com/in/craig-neesonb2808278



ABOUT

Experienced front-end developer with a demonstrated history of contributing to projects used by a global user-base. Specialising in React and TypeScript, enjoys working with diverse teams to create the best possible products for users to enjoy and for developers to happily maintain.



FRONT-END

I live and breathe in front-end development. I have extensive experience building and architecting UIs for the web and mobile using a variety of different setups. I have a deep knowledge of JavaScript with or without the context of a UIframework but greatly prefer the toolset offered by TypeScript. I have a special interest in React and the environment it provides for developers to create maintainable Uls. I have architected React projects from the ground up and enjoy working with teams to strategise around solutions to some of the bigger challenges that come with design such as statemanagement, caching, scalability For accessibility. management I have worked with Redux, MobX but more recently have steered towards React's Context API with hooks to reduce complexity. For styling I am currently a fan of styled-components in combination with styled-system for design token centralisation. Build systems that I have used include Webpack, Rollup, Parcel and Gulp.



BACK-END

I have experience contributing to C# (.NET MVC) and Java codebases in both monolithic and microservice architectures.



EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ULSTER (2013-2017)

BSc Hons Computing with DPP - 1st



HOBBIES

I have an obsessive relationship with music and so enjoy unwinding by (trying to) play a bit of guitar in the evenings. I am a techy at heart and so will also usually be tinkering with one of many unfinished sideprojects too.

EXPERIENCE

LOCATE A LOCUM

Software Developer October 2019 — Present (1 year 3 months)

- Took the lead on modernising the UI stack at Locate a Locum over the course of a year and a
 half. Introducing ambitious but achievable technical goals that challenged many cornerstones
 of how UI development was previously approached at this healthcare start-up.
- Worked with developers to set front-end standards and upskilled team members to enable faster feature development and tackle existing tech debt more effectively.
- Drove key architecture changes to allow us to move the LAL platform from a legacy web-app stack to a partially serverside-rendered React stack.
- Established LALs first fully documented React component library, working with a newly hired UX designer to refresh the Locate a Locum brand.
- Formed more maintainable patterns for retrieving and caching data retrieved from our API, establishing healthier habits when it comes to separating server state and client state and reducing the boilerplate that developers needed to write to get things done.
- Fostered the adoption of TypeScript in UI repos to increase code robustness and reduce bug regressions. At the time of writing, 40% of the main codebase has been converted to TS.
- Worked to deliver major new modules for the platform including employee leave management, scheduling, clock-in and payroll processing.

FI FXFRA

UI Engineer March 2019 — October 2019 (8 months)

Associate UI Engineer September 2018 — March 2019 (7 months)

- Worked as part of a global team to build UIs for 8 different products, used by many of the worlds "Fortune 50" companies.
- Worked in close collaboration with UX designers to create Flexera's first component library with the aim of bringing visual consistency and behaviour to many newly acquired products.
- Researched many approaches to standardising our design token usages and UI behaviours via
 the component library, eventually landing on a solution that allows us to enforce consistency
 from a design standpoint but to also remain flexible enough to suit future use-cases.
- Worked with many acquisition teams across many interesting and technically challenging products including a portal to visualise one of the worlds largest technology asset datasets, a dashboard to visualise and optimise Azure, AWS & GCP cloud resource costs, and a network-security monitoring system.

NITEC SOLUTIONS

Software Developer *November 2017 — September 2018 (11 months)*

- Delivered end-to-end sales, billing and production management systems for two large concrete factories. The systems integrated directly with production-line firmware and tracked vehicles in real-time, allowing coordinators to have a birds eye view of their operations.
- Worked heavily on internal process development, introducing CI pipelines for code delivery, private package registries for better dependency management and a modular front-end component system built with vanilla JavaScript and Handlebars.

LIBERTY INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Associate Software Engineer *June 2017 — November 2017 (6 months)*

- Worked on an integrations team to build the highly scalable infrastructure behind a greenfield insurance product.
- Gained exposure to many different languages (Kotlin, TypeScript & Scala) and AWS resources (Lambda, SQS & SNS) due to the sprawling micro-service architecture.

NITEC SOLUTIONS

Placement Developer June 2015 — August 2016 (1 year 3 months)

- Gained exposure to older stacks (classic ASP, Microsoft Silverlight) as well as newer ones (.NET MVC apps, SPAs) due to the varying range of client projects and setups.
- Created an agent program and UI to monitor the backup status of client servers and desktop machines. I also had the opportunity to build the first version of a portal on top of this infrastructure that would allow customers to visualise their backup coverage in real-time. This work was the backbone for a service that is still in daily use by many of Nitec's customers